Previously on Transformers Prime:
在上一集里
The planetary alignment,
预言中提到的星球串联现象
is nearly upon us.
近在眼前
The flaming mountain in my visions...
我见过这座喷火的高山！
A place from whence,
从这个地方
I am to harvest Dark Energon!
我可以尽情地收集黑暗能量！
I need him over here, now!
把他推过来 快！
Megatron, today you answer for your crimes against Cybertron and humanity.
威震天 今天你必须服法 向塞博特恩和人类低头认罪
Pulse rate is stabilizing.
脉搏稳定下来了
It seems the blood of Unicron I've been seeking
看来我苦苦寻找的宇宙大帝之血
is not out there, but rather, right here!
不是在星云之间 而是就在…我的脚下！
Why is the blood of Unicron erupting from beneath the Earth?
为什么宇宙大帝之血 会从地底喷发出来？
A question, Optimus,
这个问题嘛 擎天柱
that you shall take to your grave.
你到坟墓里去思考吧！
Quickly! We must pull him trough.
快！必须把他带回去
Bulk, now, now, now!
小隔 快 快 快走！！
This is merely the beginning!
好戏才刚刚开始！
I now possess enough Dark Energon to reanimate Unicron himself!
现在我拥有的黑暗能量 足以唤醒宇宙大帝！
Hahaha... yes! Hahaha...
哈哈哈…是的！哈哈哈…
Easy, Optimus.
放松 擎天柱
From the looks of things, you've been exposed to a mass of amount of Dark Energon.
从症状看来 你感染了相当多的黑暗能量
I am not the only one.
有人跟我同病相怜
Hey.
嘿
He's lucky to be alive.
能活下来 是他命大
Megatron found more of the dark stuff?
威震天又找到黑煤球了？
A Volcano full.
整整一火山的
The question is, how?
问题是 他怎么找的？
No, the question is, what,
不 问题是 他想干嘛
as in what in the world is the blood of Unicron doing here on Earth.
传说中的宇宙大帝之血 为什么会出现在地球上
The 'Cons killed a Unicorn?
虎子们杀了只独角兽？
White horse with a horn on its head...
和白马一样 不过头上长角…
prances around all sparkly?
活蹦乱跳撒欢儿那种？
Unicron, an ancient evil,
是“宇宙大帝” 远古的恶魔
whose fossilized blood comprises the matter which we call Dark Energon...
他的血液在石化之后 形成了我们所说的那种黑暗能量…
... as legend would have it.
反正…传说里是这么讲的
So you're saying, this Unicron is some kind of bogeyman?
你是说 这个宇宙大帝是某种妖怪？
Bogeyman?
妖怪？
Make believe creepy guy who hides in your closet.
大人捏造的 藏在衣柜里的怪物
No, Nurse Darby.
不 达比护士
Unicron is very real... was.
宇宙大帝确实存在…过…
That is, while I do believe he once exited,
就是说 虽然我相信他曾经存在
I just don't subscribe to the theory that his...
可我不认同那种说法 据说…
primordial life force is the substance which... harmed Raf.
构成他原始生命力的物质就是…拉夫感染的东西
I've heard it enough,
我听够了
Jack, please, help me get Raf into the car.
杰克 过来 帮我把拉夫抱上车
Mom, I thought he was doing better.
妈妈 他不是好多了吗
Raf needs to be examined by really doctors,
拉夫需要接受真人医生的检查
and Raf's family needs to know what's happened.
拉夫的家人也要了解情况
His real family.
他真正的家人
Mom, Raf's family can't protect him.
妈妈 拉夫的家人没法保护他
Not like they can.
不会像他们这样
June, it deeply grieves me that I have failed.
琼 我为自己的失败感到十分懊悔
But I will do everything in my power to ensure
但我会尽我的一切所能来确保…
that no harm comes to our human friends or any human ever again.
再也不会有人伤及我们的人类朋友 以及其他任何人类
Optimus, they are children.
擎天柱 他们还是孩子
They do not belong in your world.
他们不属于你那个世界
They should be worrying about grades, prom dates, pimples...
他们应该关心自己的成绩 舞伴 青春痘…
not their own survival!
不用担心生命危险！
Mom, Dark Energon is pouring out of the Earth.
妈妈 黑暗能量正从地下向外井喷
It doesn't do that.
这不正常
This could be about everyone's survival,
可能关系到所有人的性命
not just ours.
不光是我们的
You're coming with me,
你们必须跟我走
all three of you.
三个人都走
And they will not be coming back.
他们不会再回来了
I understand.
我理解
That's it?
这就完了？
After all we've been through together, "see ya"?
同甘共苦这么久 一句“再见”就打发了？
What about our freedom to choose?
我们不是可以自由选择吗？
That may fly on their planet,
那是他们星球的东西
but not here on Earth.
在地球上行不通
Get in.
上车
Do you really expect me to ride in a non-transforming vehicle?
你以为我会坐一辆不会变形的汽车吗？
Miko, I'm serious.
神子 我是认真的
You're not my mother.
你又不是我妈
Miko...
神子…
Neither are you!
你也不是！
Well, I am yours.
好吧 我是你妈对吧
Let's go, Jack.
我们走 杰克
She is your mom.
她毕竟是你妈妈
I'm staying.
我要留下
I'm sorry.
对不起
Ratchet, activate the GroundBridge.
救护车 启动环陆桥
No, thank you.
谢了 不必
Prime, do you copy?
擎天柱 能收到吗？
I hear you, Agent Fowler.
听到了 福勒探员
Been watching the news?
看新闻了吗？
Mother nature's got a twitch in her breaches.
大自然母亲的鼻孔发痒了
We know about the volcano.
我们知道火山喷发的事
And the quakes?
那地震呢？
Seven major temblors of the exact the same magnitude at the exact same time as the volcanic eruption.
七次大地震的震级分毫不差 而且跟火山喷发的时间完全吻合
All over the globe on different plutonic plates, in theory unrelated, if they hadn't happened...
地震分布在全球各个火山岩板块 按理说毫不相干 可它们却在…
At the exact same time.
同一时刻爆发
Check it out, more good news.
来看看 还有好消息
Freak storms unlike any the region has seen,
可怕的风暴让当地人目瞪口呆
tsunamis threaten the Canadian coast,
海啸使加拿大沿岸岌岌可危
while lightning storms pummel the Gobi Desert.
雷暴也在戈壁滩上肆虐横行
Meanwhile, electro-magnetic anomalies plague urban power grids.
与此同时 电磁异常现象在城市电网中蔓延
These abnormal global phenomena are leaving most to wonder: why now, and what next?
这些全球性的反常现象引发众人追问： 怎么会这样 还能怎么样？
Don't tell me your 'Cons've built a weather machine.
别告诉我 虎子们造了个天气控制仪
One that powerful?
能操纵天气？
Highly unlikely.
基本不可能
I do not believe the appearance of Dark Energon at this point in time to be coincidental.
我认为 黑暗能量在这个节骨眼上出现 决不是巧合
One 100, two 100...
一秒钟 两秒钟…
You OK back there, Raf?
你还好吧 拉夫？
I saw lightning.
我看见闪电了
I'm counting until the thunder...
所以在数秒 等雷声…
Huh, looks like a storm.
嗯哼 看来要起风暴了
My garden will love it.
我的花园可遭殃了
Raf, are you ok?
拉夫 你没事吧？
Hmm.
嗯
What's that?
那是什么？
No.
不…
Come on, come on, come on!
快点 快点 快点！
Bee wants us to climb into his hand.
小蜂让咱们爬到他手上！
Thank you.
谢谢
He says "You are welcome."
他说“不客气”
Reverse of your very life blood rising from the depth to become one with me.
喷涌你的生命之血 从深渊中崛起 和我融为一体！
We are back.
我们回来了
And we are glad.
我们也放心了
Are you alright?
你还好吗？
I will be. Jack...
我会好起来的 杰克…
Mom, I...
妈妈 我…
I know, me too.
我知道 我也是
But you're grounded till you're 30... 25.
但你得禁足到30岁…25岁吧
World leaders are classifying these bizarre weather patterns as a global emergency.
各国领导人将这次奇异的天气状况 定性为全球性紧急事件
Global?
全球性的？
And scientists believe the phenomena to be somehow
科学家们认为 该现象或多或少
related to the current planetary alignment.
和近期的星球串联有关
What have you learned, Prime?
有什么发现 擎天柱？
And you'd better not blow smoke up my ass...
你最好别跟我扯淡…
Special Agent Fowler.
福勒探员
We have learned this: as with the so called magma from the volcano,
这就是我们的发现：跟火山中所谓的岩浆一样
these earthquakes originated far below the Earth's crust...
这些地震源自地壳以下极深的位置
from the very center of the Earth's core in fact.
实际上 震源就在地核的正中央
Quakes don't start there, do they?
一般的地震不是这样 对吧？
Tiny tremors rising and falling in a consistent pattern, almost like...
细微的震颤呈固定的节奏起伏 就像是…
by the All Spark...
看在火种源的份上…
If I convert these data points to audio files...
如果把这些数据点 转换成声音文件的话…
What, what is it?
怎么 什么东西？
Listen.
听
Stop, Soundwave. Turn it off.
停 声波 关掉它！
I can still hear it pounding in my brain!
我的脑袋要被它震裂了！
Cybertronian heartbeat?
塞博特恩人的心跳？
How was that possible?
这怎么可能？
A heart pumps blood.
心脏泵的是血
There is nothing inside the Earth to pump except...
地球内部没有能流通的东西 除了…
Blood of Unicron.
宇宙大帝之血
I awakened.
我苏醒了！
Ok, hold on.
好吧 先打住
You mean something's living down there,
你的意思是 地底下有个活物
inside our planet?
就在地球里边？
I fear that the Earth's very core is not comprised of magma
恐怕 地核并不是由岩浆组成的
as your science has suggested, but of Dark Energon.
这和人类科学有出入 但应该是黑暗能量
And if we're hearing a spark,
如果我们听到的是火种
then Unicron is the rising darkness that the prophecy foretold.
那么宇宙大帝就是崛起的黑暗势力 如预言所说
So how do we stop this thing from rising?
好吧 怎么才能让这东西趴着不动呢？
That I'm afraid was not foretold.
恐怕预言对此并没有提及
How can something be in our Earth core and be alive?
地核里面怎么会有别的东西呢 而且还是活的？
Such a thing is not unprecedented.
这种情况不是没有先例
Before the beginning,
在创世之初
there was Primus. And there was Unicron.
世间只有原始天尊 以及宇宙大帝
One, the incarnation of creation,
一方是造物主的化身
the other... of destruction.
而另一方 是毁灭的代言人
For eons, Primus and Unicron battled,
亘古以来 原始天尊和宇宙大帝频繁交战
the balance of power shifting between them more times than could be counted.
二者实力不相上下 无数个回合难分胜负
Only by creating the Thirteen--
后来 原始天尊创造出十三位领袖――
the original Primes preceded me--
也就是我的几位前任领袖――
was Primus finally able to defeat Unicron and cast him out.
才使自己最终战胜了宇宙大帝 并将他流放
Primus became one with the very core of our planet,
原始天尊融入我们星球的核心
creating life through the Well of All Sparks,
通过火种源之井创造生命
while Unicron was never to be heard from again... until now.
而宇宙大帝从此销声匿迹 如今却重返江湖
Maybe we can find the hole this kuggo Con left when he dug himself all the way down there,
也许我们能找到这个钻地虎当年进入地心时 挖出的洞口
and fill it full of explosives.
在里面填满炸药
Agent Fowler,
福勒探员
I do not believe that Earth became Unicron's home,
我认为 并非是宇宙大帝想在地球安家
but rather that with time and gravitational force,
而是随着时间推移和重力作用
debris collected around this slumbering titan.
星体碎屑聚拢在这个沉睡的巨人周围
Forming your Earth itself.
这才造就了你们的地球
And he's only awakening now, due to the magnetic pull created by the planetary alignment?
他现在才睡醒 是因为星球串联形成了强大的磁吸力吗？
Ok, what happens now when Unicron wakes up from his billion-year nap?
好吧 宇宙大帝用几十亿年打了个盹儿 现在要干嘛？
Yeah, does he stretch and ka-pow... Earth pup to dust?
是啊 难道他伸个懒腰就“砰”的一声 地球灰飞烟灭了？
You don't know, do you?
你也不知道 对吧？
My guess is that Unicron has transcended physical form as we know it.
我猜想 宇宙大帝的身躯应该和传说中一样 硕大无比
Nonetheless, we must find a way to ensure that this "force of nature" never fully awakens.
尽管如此 我们必须想办法确保这个“不可抗力”…
The fate of your planet depends upon it.
你们星球的命运在此一举
Lord Megatron, our cargo hold is nearly filled with the dark substance.
威震天陛下 货舱差不多被黑暗物质堆满了
I recommend a retreat,
我建议收兵
the troops are growing weak from its effects.
战士们受黑暗能量的影响 越来越虚弱
And yet I grow stronger.
但我却感到空前强大
Airachnid, you're in command until my return.
毒蜘蛛 你负责指挥 等我回来
Your return from where, Master?
您这是要去哪儿 主人？
From my audience with Unicron.
去会会宇宙大帝
I feel your presents,
我感受到您的存在
share your very spark.
分享您尊贵的火种！
I call on you as my Lord and Master, almighty Unicron.
我专程来拜访您 我的阁下和主人 全能的宇宙大帝！
Who would speak to me?
谁在和我说话？
Your servant most humble,
您最谦卑的仆人
Megatron, leader of the Decepticons,
威震天 霸天虎的统帅
and your very Herald,
您忠诚的使者
the one who wielded the Dark Energon which binds us,
是我运用黑暗能量 将你我联系在一起
to awaken you once again. The prophecy has been fulfilled.
使您再次苏醒 最终验证了预言！
It is only the beginning of what we shall accomplish, together!
我们即将共创一番大业 强强联手！
For you shall rule this planet and those who walk upon it through me.
为您统治这颗星球 连同所有的生命 我将义不容辞！
Pride for fool.
痴人说梦！
How dare you think yourself capable of summoning my life force?
你竟然以为 自己有资格召唤我的生命力？
I rise because I have deemed my time.
我苏醒 是因为我感觉时机已到！
Master, I did not mean to overstep.
主人 我无意以下犯上
Silence, worm!
闭嘴 蠕虫！
I have no need of your lowly assistance.
我无需一个下人插手此事
Please, my Lord.
求您了 我的陛下
I exist only to serve you.
我此生只为您效忠！
What is this I sense?
这是什么味道？
The taint of Primus? Here?!
原始天尊的遗骨吗？这里也有？！
That is Optimus,
那是擎天柱
the last of the Primes, our sworn enemy.
最后一个领袖 我们的死敌
You profess loyalty to me,
你口口声声说对我尽忠
yet allow a disciple of Primus to live?!
却放任原始天尊的门徒活到今天？！
I will destroy him for you!
我会为您消灭他！
His screams will be heard...
他的惨叫会响彻…
I grow weary of your prattle.
你的花言巧语我听够了
Surely if you had the power to destroy this Prime,
显然 如果你有实力消灭这个领袖
you would have done so already.
你早该做到了
I will deal with him myself.
我还是亲自处理他吧
Ratchet, this epicenter is consistent with the findings of the others.
救护车 这个震源的特征和其他几处基本一致
Its terrain is rich in ore.
地下矿藏非常丰富
So what does that tell us?
那是什么意思？
It follows that the natural medals in your Earth
这表示 你们地球上的天然金属矿
would be extensions of Unicron-- his limbs if you will.
就是宇宙大帝的扩展部分 相当于他的四肢
So, he did have his morning stretch,
这么说 他的确伸了个懒腰
which is why these quakes happened.
所以才引发了地震
Optimus, I'm detecting a swell of Unicron's spark activity.
擎天柱 我发现宇宙大帝火种的活性急剧增强
Rest assured, Ratchet,
放心吧 救护车
I will proceed with vigilance.
我会提高警惕的
Do you know me, follower of Primus?
你认识我吗 原始天尊的追随者？
Unicron, the Chaos Bringer.
宇宙大帝 混沌制造者
Good.
很好
Now know me as Unicron, your destroyer!
现在 称我为宇宙大帝――你的毁灭者！
I humbly request your ear, Lord Unicron.
我恳求您听我一言 尊敬的宇宙大帝
And what would a Prime be so compelled to say to me?
一个如此低三下四的领袖 到底要说什么？
I make this appeal not for myself,
我的请求不是为自己
but for this planet which you constitute, and the beings who inhabit it.
而是为这个由您构建的星球 以及栖居其上的生命体
Human kind relies upon you, for life, sustenance.
人类依赖于您 才能繁衍生息
Your resurrection will only result in the destruction of a spices
您的复活只会导致这个物种走向毁灭
which evolved from the seeds of your very greatness.
而它恰恰是由您的伟大子孙孕育而生的
So this humankind of whom you speak,
那么你所说的这种人类
you consider them my progeny?
它们也算是我的后裔吗？
Indeed.
没错
Parasites! They, too, shall know my wrathful hand,
是寄生虫！它们也会领教到我的怒火
once I am finished with you.
但我要先和你把账算清！
The line of Primus has grown weak in my absence, and thus you shall fall.
多日不见 原始天尊的氏族竟如此衰败 今天你陨落无疑！
That outcome is inevitable,
汽车人固有一死
but not on this day.
但今天不是时候！
Yes, disciple of Primes, on this very day.
是的 原始天尊的门徒 就在今天
For Unicron may be one, but we all are Unicron.
宇宙大帝之名独一无二 但我们都是宇宙大帝！